I heard the recording in progress when I joined.
Oh, you're muted.
Wait, hold. Oh, yeah, it says so in my top right as well.
Recording. Uh, yeah.
Are you there? Sorry, I had to switch, uh,
my internet. I should be good now.
Okay, great. Yeah, I was just saying
that in my top right it says recording,
so I think that we are good.
Yes, yes. All right.
I logged in a little early today just
to make sure the polls were all set up.
Um, okay, cool. So there's a little bit of a boring
black screen to edit out,
but, uh, better than not having a video.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. No worries.
That's an easy to just see where we start.
Yeah. Um, cool.
Yeah, everything is good.
Let me look over my whole screen here. Okay.
I need everything. Where is this?
So I have two of these open,
so one of these does not need to be here.
Okay.
How are you feeling? It's a dense one for you today.
Yeah, it's a lot. It's a lot to cover.
Um, you know, I think it'll be fine. Mm-hmm.
I'm just, uh, you know, I'm a wing it guy, so,
uh, I, I think it'll be fine.
I, you know, like I, for me, I just, I need
to go over the content.
I'm not sure how you do it. If you had to present.
I just need to go over the content
and in this case, I'm, I'm really like repurposing.
So it's, it's not that I'm, uh, you know,
but I need to understand it first, which I, I do.
Um, so that's really kind of key for me.
And then after that, I'm just sort of, I was listening
to Dale and then making more like mental bullets
of like, this is how I say that.
Um, yeah. While also like just staying true
to the, to the content.
Mm-hmm.
Um, my only question is, uh, following the breakout,
it just says facilitate return in the chat,
share key insight that emerged from you.
Uh, I'll just be reading those out.
We don't wanna sort of call on folks.
We likely won't have the time today, or,
You know, I don't know. I,
you know, it was interesting.
I don't know how you felt, but I, I,
I noticed in the first session that we moved, I,
you know, it's the first time we've done this.
Um, or, you know, I, I,
the first time I've done this in the presenting side,
and so the thing with me is I am not, um,
I'm not like looking at the clock
and I'm not sort of, where am I?
That's probably a bad thing.
Um, so maybe keep an eye on it, especially today
'cause there's a lot of content I need to cover.
Mm-hmm. With that said,
I noticed like we finished fairly quickly.
Mm-hmm. I remember when we went to the q and a, 'cause the q
and a typically, I remember it being about 10 minutes.
Mm-hmm. And 'cause you do next steps,
and then we'll go to q and a.
Mm-hmm. And so I remember looking at the clock,
and I think we were, you know, it was about 20 to 30 minutes
of q and a now.
We did end up taking that time, so it was pretty smooth.
Um, but I remember thinking like, oh, wow, we, uh, sort
of breeze through this first session.
So I think today we'll be different.
'cause obviously I don't know
how many slides like total it is,
but it, it, there's a lot
of information I'm going over today opposed
to just like saying, Hey, this is
what this is, this is how it's gonna work.
Um, so my
Guess, my guess is that, yeah, my guess is too
that there were so many returning folks that a lot
of the initial setup questions
or, you know, places where folks would just sort of be like,
can you say that another way?
Or Can I ask a clarifying question? Just wouldn't apply.
Yeah. It also felt like of the folks who were new, um,
they were very tech savvy, so it wasn't like we were dealing
with these owner operators who are like,
I'm having trouble walking
On the internet. Yeah. And the, the
vast majority of people, like probably
se 70%, maybe 60% were pre like, from the beta.
Mm-hmm. So they certainly,
I gave them some perspective on their questions
because it's like, you, here's a few ways you could go about
doing that, but it's ultimately, it's your choice.
Like anything in business
or life, there's no one way to do anything.
It's just kind of whatever you feel like is,
is the right approach for you.
Yeah. But no, I feel good.
Like I said, I mean, for me, I, I just need
to deliver the content
and hopefully knowing that I'm, like,
I'm basically just going slide by slide
and, um, conveying information about that.
Um, hopefully I'm in the ballpark,
but I, I have not been, like, looking at it more from the,
from the angle of like, I need to do 20 minutes here.
Kinda like the run a show does.
I'm just like, let me look at the slide.
I listened to what I went through a couple of times
and listened to Dale do it.
And so I'm like, okay, like I, I understand the information
and I'm saying the same thing.
It might just be in a slightly different way.
Uh, is there a way that, you know, for example,
say a question pops up, um, you know,
like really in the thick of you delivering a piece,
is there a way that you would like me to signal just sort
of maybe taking a pause and going to that question?
Or do you wanna wait till there's a natural break?
I also feel like the breakout, um, time is a good time
for us to just sort of connect and sort of go through
and see if anything has emerged
that we wanna get to before. Yeah,
Good question. I would
say for you, what, what I did as the coil,
sometimes I would answer it in the chat.
Yeah. If you see people are asking, like starting
to ask questions, I'm not looking at the chat, obviously.
Yeah. But, um, you can do a couple of things, like,
we'll bring this up a bit.
Like you can just respond back to that person.
Like, we'll bring this up in the q and a portion.
Um, if you can answer it, great. Mm-hmm.
Um, real time is always the best,
but those are kind of the, the two angles I would take.
And then at the end, whether it's I finish a section
or like, if it happens right away, um,
or at the, towards the end, you can, you can either,
you can do two things.
You can go, Hey, I see a couple
of people asking questions in the chat.
Just so you know, we have a lot to cover
and we have a, we always end each session with a q
and a, so I'll be sure to sort of like, you can,
because the chat might keep going, maybe write them
or copy paste them somewhere.
Mm-hmm. Then, you know, Josh asks this
and Midori asks this earlier, can we start there?
And then we'll get to,
you know, some of these questions here.
So mm-hmm. That's how I would do it.
Okay. Sounds good. Where
are our participants?
Or till
I just kicked a note taker,
but there was no one as accompanying that note taker.
Hmm. Alright, well,
Uh, I just used the link that was in the curriculum
cohort four, like that's how I jumped in.
Yeah, that's the, that's the correct link,
right? There's not gonna be others.
Yeah, me too. Around. It should be the same one,
but I, I, since I'm not the host either, like I'm,
I'm just going into circle
and clicking from the, the actual event, so No problem.
Alright.
Still the good weather over there,
It's cold. I mean, for
me, you know, so it's, it's been,
it's been like, it's probably as cold as it, it gets here.
So in the morning it's been as cold as about 38 degrees
and it, it, you know, heats up a little bit like midday.
Mm-hmm. Like this morning it was 40, uh, last couple days,
I think it's been 40, but it's coldest it gets,
is probably high thirties and, um,
but yeah, I mean, we're gonna be
whenever like people like you
or all over the US, like it's crazy cold.
We're gonna get our cold front too in this vortex,
but it's, um, you know, I'm certainly not dealing
with anything that, um, you
or anybody in else in like,
real winter places throughout the United States.
I mean, it's chaos. Yeah.
I know you, I, 'cause you tell me,
and I I've shared with vpo, who I told you is in Minnesota
and it's, uh, it's been wild to, to just see some
of the temperatures he posts
and, um, you know, certain people are losing power.
There's, there's a lot of stuff going on.
Just gonna start admitting folks.
Well, you're early.
I've got 1259. Hello.
At 58. Hey Dawn, uh, little early,
but we're, we're just gonna wait a couple of minutes here
so you can, um,
You can relax.
No worries. How's your Wednesday going so far?
I'll finish breakfast. Okay.
Where are you, Don? Where are you located?
I'm in, uh, I'm in, uh, California. Oh,
Cool. Whereabouts?
It's, uh, yeah, about 10 o'clock.
I'm just north of San Francisco
and a little bird called, uh, runner Park.
Okay, cool. Yeah.
Interesting. The times we live in. Yeah,
We were just talking about the weather.
'cause MAD's in Toronto
and I, I'm in Florida, so it's, it's certainly, you know,
cold for us, Don, I'm in a sweater right now,
you know, but, oh
Man. Not
anything, like, a lot of people like Midori and,
and other people on our team
and throughout the US are dealing with a lot of, uh,
crazy times right now 'cause of the weather. So
Yeah. This, this is
true. So I'll just mention to you
that I have, I've evolved into, uh, back in, I'm,
I'm working with this construction company almost
exclusively at this point, you know, trying
to rescue them from a big downturn
that experienced here in the Bay Area from, uh, uh,
people are freaked out about, uh, interest rates
and financial risk.
Sure. Putting,
putting off discretionary pro, uh, projects.
And so volume is being cut in half for contractors pre, uh,
a lot of, lot of comments
and that, so we're knuckling down, tightening the,
tightening up the, the, the rigging.
Thought I'd mentioned that while we had a second.
Yeah. Getting a couple people joining here.
Great. Good. See everybody.
But Dora, you made me co-host, right?
If you haven't, please do. Welcome everybody.
Alright,
we'll just wait probably about 30 seconds here,
so a few more people log in.
Welcome, welcome everyone. Nice to see everyone today.
Just giving folks a moment to get settled and join the call.
I know we're calling in from a range
of places and time zones.
Yeah. Christian, good to see you on the call.
I think this is, you, you,
you weren't on the first call, right?
And then Benny. That's right. Yeah. Good to see you as well.
Thanks for showing up on the session today. Yes.
I missed the first one. Yeah, yeah. Good, good. I'm excited.
Alright. I am going to, let me gimme one moment.
I'm gonna shut my door
And I hope you're all enjoying a productive
and healthy week.
I'm gonna get started in just a moment.
We may still have a few folks joining late,
but Josh, if you're feeling good, I think we can, yeah,
I think we can get started. Get
started in the interest of time.
Perfect. All right.
Uh, for those of you who were here on Monday, it's
so very nice to see you again.
Uh, for those of you new today, my name is Midori
and I am looking forward to connecting with you.
I'll over the next, uh, few weeks.
I'll be co-facilitator here with you
for this fo fourth cohort of the Empower Labs program.
I'm Josh is co-pilot today, uh,
and Josh is leading today's session.
Uh, we're building on everything from Monday
initial setup session.
Uh, we're diving a little deeper, uh, into
what we're calling the invisible structure of business.
Uh, and while that might feel very conceptual now,
if we've succeeded today, uh,
you will gain some clarity on your organization's current AI
standing and as well, well as
identify a concrete path forward.
Um, this session is really delivered to deliver, uh,
this session is really designed to deliver some
of those aha moments.
Uh, I'm gonna start with a little milestone, uh, check-in.
Uh, so before we get started with today's content, uh,
just a quick review of where we're hoping everyone is today.
Uh, at this point, we hope
that you have logged into your circle account.
We hope that you've had the opportunity
to introduce yourself to the community,
and we really do encourage, um, you to interact, uh,
with each other's posts.
This is our community, uh,
and it's where we're gonna be sharing our goals, our wins,
our questions, our frustrations, our tips and tricks.
Uh, I wanted to uplift, um, Lee, who on Monday, uh,
brought a copy paste issue up to the group's attention
and then solved it using ai, uh, faster than our team could.
So, really appreciate you.
And that's exactly what, uh, we want, um,
from Circle and this community.
Uh, the crucial next step is that you have activated a paid,
uh, cl cl Claude account.
And so that is pro or teams.
Um, and this is really gonna be
essential for your progressing.
And finally, um, following our first session, we hope
that you've created your master prompt version one.
Uh, and so just
to quickly check in on everyone's current progress
and ensure alignment, I'm gonna launch a poll now.
Uh, we're gonna be closely monitoring, uh, completion rates,
particularly within the Circle platform.
So a big thank you to everyone
who has completed the modules through the circle hub.
Uh, and that all is coming.
Alright, just looking at, uh,
okay.
So it looks like, um, 73%
of you have answered yes.
Uh, you have, uh, completed, uh, the work
and you are at where we hope to be today.
Um, 27% of you answered no.
And so we're just gonna really, um, uh, ask
for folks to really try and get, uh, caught up
because things really start to accelerate in the, uh,
in the days that come.
And specifically, you know,
we wanna make sure everybody sort of completes what we need
to do by Friday,
because you'll need that for Friday's session.
I know a few people, Midori,
you know, just sort of joined.
I know Benny was one of them,
but a couple people just popped in.
So they, they're getting their bearings, uh, you know,
caught up with the foundational stuff,
but now that they're here, they should, you know, it's not,
it's not very time consuming this first
week with the three sessions.
So,
Okay.
Uh, so here's what we're covering today.
Uh, it's really three big things.
Uh, we're gonna begin
by dissecting the three essential
components of any business.
Um, this framework will provide
a completely fresh perspective
for viewing your organization.
Uh, and we're gonna be relying a bit on Clayton
Christensen's framework for this.
Uh, the next thing we're gonna do is we're going
to explore the five stages of AI enabled,
uh, business evolution.
Uh, this section is really designed
to help you determine your current position
and visualize the potential path forward, um,
and really sort of clarify a lot of your questions
around next steps in AI integration.
And finally, the third thing that we're gonna cover
is the actual evolution of your business.
Um, this is not just theory, uh,
Josh is gonna provide practical, uh, executable steps
that you can implement, uh, immediately.
Uh, so hopefully that is, uh, clear to folks.
Um, if so, it would be helpful if you drop a yes
in the chat, and if anyone needs a further
clarification, do let us know.
Excellent. Okay, Josh,
I'm gonna hand it over to you.
Excellent. Thanks, Midori.
And yeah, we're jumping in today by laying the,
the foundation for the work ahead as was mentioned.
So the first part of today's session is focused on
what we call the invisible structure of business.
That's the underlining dynamics that determine
how an organization actually operates, not just
how it looks on paper.
So our goal is to develop a clear framework
for understanding three key parts of a business,
and more importantly, how those parts interact.
This gives us a practical way to analyze
how an organization functions day to day
and why it may struggle with change, adoption,
or innovation of any kind.
We've entered a period of significant accelerating change.
This isn't the first time in history
that businesses have faced transformation at this scale,
and it certainly won't be the last.
But what remains consistent is that organizations made up
of people, systems
and processes tend to encounter very specific
friction points when change is introduced.
So the, the key idea that will reinforce today is that
AI doesn't replace the need for structure.
It exposes the absence of it process is
what allows change to be absorbed, repeated, and scaled.
And without it, even the best tools fail to deliver results.
So We wanna unpack three specific areas
of a business and why this matters at this moment in time
with this particular lane in change management.
So as Midori mentioned, we want to draw from some
of Clayton Christensen's work.
If you don't know, he was a Harvard business professor
who wrote a number of books focused on the
contributions in the era of innovation and disruption.
So disruptive innovation is, is kind
of a term he's credited with.
And in Christiansen's work, he identified
that there are these three things
that exist in any organization that's going
to possess a set of resources.
That's, that's the what.
So assets that a company can use,
processes are the how,
the way those resources work together.
So resources could be people, could be human resources.
So resources are the what processes are the how.
And in his framework, the priorities are the why
or the, the values
or the principles that guide the decisions that we make.
So these come together.
And there there's kind of a traditional view
to say things like, our company needs to hire developers
with cloud arch architecture experience.
That's a specific example on, on the slides here.
And you probably have some version of
that in your own vocabulary, right?
So this is view that we need more people
or we need more capital, more equipment, more,
um, real estate.
Maybe we need more patents or intellectual property,
or we need reputation and, and trust for our brand.
These are the traditional view examples
of needing more of these things.
Um, there's a traditional view of process,
which is things like our manufacturing process
or a customer acquisition process,
or fulfillment and improvement.
These are all traditional views or processes.
Um, oftentimes processes are viewed as cross-functional,
meaning an onboarding process might take multiple steps
across three different departments in order to be completed.
And there's validity in, in that view of process.
When we look at that plus the traditional view
of priorities, there are hidden priorities
in every organization.
And sometimes we are enlightened about this
and we do the work together as a team of identifying
what priorities are things like our strategy on what markets
to enter or exit resource allocation,
defining our priorities, where to invest time
and money operations,
and what quality standards to maintain,
which segments to focus on for the customer
or the way we choose to innovate relative to
what new capabilities can develop as a type of priority.
Sometimes organizations prioritize one particular view over
another because they're seeking to
dominate a particular niche in the marketplace, for example.
So these traditional views have validity.
And, and Christensen made a few observations about this.
Some of these include that oftentimes
resources are transferable between contexts.
Processes are often optimized for specific tasks
and could be harder to repurpose.
And he offered this as an explanation.
That is one reason that organizations
with excellent resources can still fail if the processes
don't effectively deploy those resources.
So in this moment of kind of AI transformation,
AI enablement, the various tools
that we have at our disposal represent just
that they are tools.
They can be viewed as resources, they might be resources
that help us deploy other resources effectively.
They might be resources that help us become more effective
or efficient as people.
There is also a liability present here.
We need to just identify.
And that is, if we aren't effective in understanding
how process fits into this, we may run the risk
of using the tool and making things worse.
Sometimes internally, like we, we joke about
piling AI on top of a bad strategy, it makes it worse,
or AI just
as another ingredient in the mix doesn't
necessarily solve anything.
So this mentality that we often think of scaling
about adding resources first, um, you know, that tends
to lead us in a direction
of a linear scale versus an exponential scale.
And so Christensen insight here is
that if you add a resource
or resources to a business that doesn't have good processes,
you simply scale your problems.
And maybe some of you can relate to that.
So you, you can refer to a couple
of his works mentioned here, like the investors dilemma
and the innovator solution books, uh, which is what we're,
we're sort of drawing this from as well.
Okay, so before we jump into the five stages, I,
I wanna share something I've personally seen play out over
and over again, um,
with business owners mostly on their sales operations,
where I've focused a lot of my career.
So for years I, I've had kind of a front row seat of
how companies try to scale sales,
and almost every time
I see a business reaches a certain point, there's, um,
a realization that hits
and they think we need a better tool to manage this.
So that's looking at CRMs, automation platforms, AI tools,
whatever the flavor of the year happens to be.
And, and the belief is almost always the same.
And that's if we implement the right tool,
it gives us the sales process we're missing.
And, and I can tell you,
I I've watched countless business owners assume that's
software will magically sort of create structure,
whether it's qualification criteria,
a predictable sales process, follow up, logic, handoffs, all
of these things that are sort of messy and unclear.
But what becomes immediately clear is
that the tool isn't the problem.
The, the absence of defined followed process is
the, the best implementers are always honest about this.
And I know I am. It's, I'll say something like,
I can absolutely help you automate your sales operation,
but I can only automate what already exists
because software on its own doesn't create
process, it scales it.
So that realization hits hard with a lot of people
through many different areas of their business.
This certainly isn't just a sales problem,
it's really a business problem.
And so the, the takeaway for, for you all is,
is really the same is that process is the prerequisite
tools, including AI don't solve the lack of clarity.
They expose it. And that's why as, as we sort of walk
through these five stages of AI enabled business evolution,
it's, it's critical to understand that advancement
doesn't come from just adopting better tools.
First, it comes from defining how your business is supposed
to work before you try to scale or automate it.
So we'll now kind of dive into an overview on
how businesses evolve from human operated to
AI driven organizations.
Okay, so we're, we're gonna walk through these five stages
that we've identified.
Uh, I'm sure you can parse this in different ways,
but there are at least five stages that exist
as we approach the, the subject of AI and,
and all of these tools and resources.
Stage one, we've labeled the heroic effort
or owner operated, owner operator reality.
So, um, that's organizations.
I'm, I'm sure some of us here, uh,
or maybe many of us here are, are sort of stuck in this spot
and we'll, we'll talk about
that a bit more about the details,
but that's sort of the heroic effort.
Business. Stage two is we've defined
as the, the, the team led business, team led business is
where you've been able to delegate effectively,
and I I'll say here, delegation is a form of automation,
not the only form certainly,
but delegation is part of this conversation.
And oftentimes if we're we're struggling to delegate
to another person, we're also going to struggle to delegate
to an AI agent or a tool in that same regard.
So the, the mentality of of setting something up
to be delegated is a critical part of this evolution.
And the third stage we identified is the process driven
business where it's not just led by a group
of well delegated team members,
but there's a level of maturity around documentation
and the processes within the organization.
When we get to stage three, we're then able
to objectively look at documented process
and understand how we might approach
making improvements to it.
It's, it's in this place where we no longer are,
are doing everything from scratch
for the first time in a different way.
We've now identified that there's a way that we tend to do
a particular thing, stage four,
where labeling ai augmented,
which is an enhanced version of stage three.
And, and most of us here have, have probably seen a, a bit
of a vision of what stage four might look like.
There could be a few of us here that,
that actually have moved into stage four
context in maybe a particular area,
maybe not the entire organization or business,
but there might be a, a particular function
or discipline that you've begun to experiment.
And, and most of us here,
I believe are particularly interested in getting
to stage four from wherever we are currently.
Mainly in focusing on the, the one thing
that we mentioned in the first session.
Now stage five is what we're defining as AI operated,
which is primarily automated.
And our view
of stage five is largely theoretical at this moment.
It is coming quickly.
There's a handful of examples we're starting to see.
Um, but in terms of overarching stage five business,
I'm not sure we have great examples of what
that looks like quite yet.
We're getting closer, but not really anything to point
to in his example right now to say, um,
their stage five business.
Okay, so there's a number
of slides here in the deck discussing all of these stages,
and I'm, I'm gonna go through them fairly quickly
and what I'm gonna do is,
is just kind of hit some highlights.
These slides will of course exist in circle for you to kind
of refer back to.
I imagine that following our live session,
you might wanna go back
and spend a little time just sort of reflecting on each
of these kind of distinctions for each of these stages.
Um, most of us are, are probably going
to have a pretty good sense
of which stage we're currently at in this particular moment,
and we're gonna do a poll for this a bit later.
Uh, but just so we can get everybody's position on this,
but I don't wanna spend a lot of time on detail.
I just wanna kind of introduce this
and have everyone sort of register
where they believe they are at this moment.
So stage one is all about owner operated reality.
So this is where everything depends on the owner
or the founder or the leader.
Some of you are maybe beyond owner,
founder led organizations,
but a lot of the organizations we work with are founder led.
And so it's that bottleneck at the top
where everything funnels through the individual
and those resources rely deeply on time, energy,
and relationships of the person, the founder,
the owner, the leader.
And so there's, there's lots of ad hoc process
and priorities tend to be sort
of defined in more reactive ways, um,
or, you know, who's ever kind of yelling the loudest.
Um, there's limitations of stage one.
There's limitations on scale.
Uh, we have some numbers here that we've included,
but these are not fixed numbers by any means.
They're just here to, to represent an acknowledgement
that there is a certain number of direct reports
that any one individual can maintain.
And so there's, there's a ceiling on that
and there's a point in any organization's development
where it's, it's not gonna be able to grow further
if it's dependent on its founder or its key leader.
So we would talk about and,
and kind of label this key person risk,
and that's one of the things to consider.
So there's, there's knowledge risk
and there's the decision bottlenecks that exist with that.
Okay? In stage two, A, a team led business is defined
by a statement like, we built a leadership team
that can run the business.
A good marker of stage two is when a founder
or a leader comes to work and kind of shows up for a meeting
and the team says, we don't need you, we got this.
Um, and if it's true, by the way, they're not just sort
of saying that to, to push the person away.
If it's actually in fact true, then it's a,
a really good indicator that we are squarely at stage two.
This is, um, rules
and accountability, consistent approaches,
and at least a measure of cohesive leadership,
team decision making, awareness of the market, awareness
of internal limitations
and priorities that can be established as a team.
Um, there's limitations in stage two.
Uh, uh, you know, you, you still have key person risk
and perhaps there are consistent approaches to things
and we tend to approach things in the same way,
but often still miss full documentation and consistency.
So the mindset shift to go from stage one to stage two
is from doer to leader.
So wherever you are, whatever your role
or position in your organization, um,
I know we have a number of us here that are, that are CEOs
or founders or presidents or, or key leaders.
And, and then there's the other of us here
that either represent a key leadership role.
You might simply be a member
of a team in an individual contributor role,
whichever it is, it doesn't matter.
It is still a mindset shift to move from doer to leader.
This is important to understand.
So whether you're a founder eliminating that bottleneck
or if you're a member of a team, this is just as important
because to move up in an organization, one attribute
of good leadership is that you can create leaders
who then create other leaders.
So two layers down from your own role,
whatever your role is, you can look in the mirror
for a moment and ask, am I developing my abilities
to create leaders who then create leaders?
It becomes the idea that my job isn't to do everything.
It's to build and lead a team that can,
a process driven organization can be summarized
by a simple idea, which is we build systems
that work consistently regardless of who is operating.
There's many examples of mature organizations
that demonstrate what it looks like in practice.
And one of the most commonly referenced
and earliest models would be in like the franchise system.
McDonald's is often used
as like a global standard for this reason.
We all know what it is also.
But like beginning with the McDonald's brothers and,
and then later scaled by Ray Crock, the,
the company built an organization designed to operate
with a high degree of consistency at massive scale.
Like I said, most of us here, regardless of where we live,
have experienced a McDonald's at some point.
And while maybe menus vary slightly based on local
ingredients, um, and,
and maybe regional preferences, the core experience remains
remarkably consistent.
The way the food's prepared, the sequence of steps,
the timing and sort of the quality standards are all driven
by clearly defined process.
And that consistency isn't accidental, it's the result
of intentional system design.
And it sort of illustrates what's possible when an
organization prioritizes process over individual dependency.
Um, at this stage, there's still limitations.
The first is rigidity.
Once processes are documented, they can start to harden.
And what was meant to sort
of create consistency can slowly turn into inflexibility,
making it harder for teams to adapt when conditions change.
Second is documentation overhead.
Maintaining SOPs does take real time and effort.
And as a business grows, keeping documentation accurate,
updated and usable sort of becomes a job in itself.
And that work often competes with execution.
The third is, you know, change resistance.
Once people get used to, you know,
the standard way things are done, modifying a process,
even when it's clearly better, can sort of create friction.
Teams may resist changes simply
because the system feels familiar.
And finally, there's scale complexity.
As organizations grow beyond roughly 150 people,
process alone isn't enough.
You know, coordination, communication
and decision-making start to strain.
And then entirely new systems are sort of required
to manage that level of scale.
So there, there's a lot of opportunity here.
So this is the key mindset shift
as we move from stage two to stage three.
At this point, leadership stops being about managing people
day to day, and it starts being about designing systems.
So the, the, the shift is simple but profound, right?
As I mentioned, my job isn't to manage people.
Uh, my job is to design systems that manage themselves.
So instead of relying on individual effort, heroics
or constant oversight, the focus becomes documenting
what works, turning it into repeatable processes,
and reducing dependency on any single person.
This is where consistency starts to replace effort.
Now, looking ahead, this is also
what makes AI augmentation possible in later stages,
because when systems are, are clear,
AI can take on the routine work, allowing humans to,
to focus on what actually matters, which,
you know, that means two things.
Humans handle the exceptions,
and humans focus on being exceptional.
So the, the goal here isn't
to remove humans from the system,
and maybe a lot of beta people can relate to this.
It's, it's really about amplifying human capability
by designing systems that, that do the heavy lifting
AI augmented at stage four, I think most of us are excited
and energized to move into this space, right?
Well, what is that? It's when AI handles the routine
so that humans can focus on the exceptional.
So humans can handle the exceptions,
but also humans can handle the things that require
to be exceptional, right?
So it's automating both routine things so
that we can focus our attention as people
and things that no machine can ever do.
It's, it's looking for ways to amplify human experience and,
and really result in what we would call semi-automated
workflows that are sort of assisted by,
but still require human judgment,
although that judgment may be enhanced by the insights
and analysis that AI provides.
Okay? Even at stage four,
there are still real limitations we need to be honest about.
The first is the AI skill gap.
Most organizations don't yet have a workforce that is truly
AI literate or, or sort of comfortable collaborating
with AI systems.
That gap is very, very real in this moment.
And closing it is, is sort of part
of the work we're doing together.
Everyone here is is on that journey and,
and the goal is to move through it intentionally.
Second is, is technology complexity.
The AI ecosystem is noisy.
I'm not sure if you all feel that,
but you know, there are countless tools, models, platforms
and integrations.
And even at the basic level, questions like,
which LLM should we use or,
or what tools actually matter can feel very overwhelming.
So these systems require kind
of ongoing management decisions and refinement.
Third is sort of quality control.
AI outputs still require human oversight.
So you've, you've likely already experienced this firsthand
by maybe reviewing outputs, adjusting prompts,
applying judgment, and sort
of deciding what's usable and what isn't.
AI accelerates your work,
but humans are still responsible for sort
of validating results.
And finally, there's competitive pressure.
Any ai, you know, uh, today will eventually diminish
as adoption s spreads.
So the shift is from system designer
to technology integrator.
At this stage, the, the question is no longer
how do I design better processes?
It becomes, how do I intentionally integrate AI into those
processes to amplify human capability?
The goal isn't automation for its own sake.
It's building hybrid teams, humans
and AI working together each doing what they do best.
So that means identifying where AI can enhance human work,
designing workflows that that leverage both strengths,
that being deliberate about where judgment, creativity,
and decision making stay human.
Stage four is
where organizations stop experimenting casually with AI
and start integrating it intentionally.
So building repeatable, human centered AI assisted workflows
that actually scale
Stage five AI operated automated business.
This is the business that runs itself within
parameters we've set.
So we will just acknowledge
that it's largely theoretical at this point and,
and we can kind of continue to, to move in
that direction as things progress.
Okay. Still limitations.
Um, we would still have to think about governance,
compliance, privacy, what in fact, you know,
is sustainable advantage if we do over automate, you know,
do we reduce adaptability?
You have context rot or brain rot.
Both of those things are a real thing.
And, and what happens when the automations that we engineer
begin to be used to train each other?
You know, that's, uh, there, there's all kinds of questions
that we are barely at a place
of even asking about stuff like that yet,
let alone having an understanding of,
but it's sure to progress fast over these next few years.
We like this idea that the mindset
from technology integrator
to stage five requires being like an orchestra conductor.
So there's, there's still going to be a role for humans
to orchestrate these various systems and processes
and pieces of technology as we go forward.
Just like an orchestra conductor sort
of recognizes various parts of the orchestra, you want
to at least have working knowledge and,
and understanding of how they fit together so
that you can begin to effectively
orchestrate all of the above.
So it's about setting the vision and the standards,
and then let those systems execute
and ultimately begin optimizing themselves
with some oversight.
Okay, it's, it's worth pausing for a moment to talk about
how value evolves across these five stages.
The numbers you see on this slide aren't meant to be exact
or, or predictive for every business,
but they, they give us useful reference points for how value
is typically created as organizations mature.
One of the most important metrics to understand here is,
is earnings per employee
or EBITDA per employee at a basic level.
This tells us how effectively a,
a business turns people systems and process into profit.
And you can think of this simply as like your p
and l divided by number of employees.
So that could include revenue per employee
or gross profit per employee,
and ultimately EBITDA per employee, which is, uh,
the metric buyers, investors,
and sort of operators care about most.
Now, decades of data consistently show that each stage
has a natural ceiling for earnings per employee.
In stage one values driven almost entirely
by owner effort
and expertise, there's usually a, a hard cap there.
So it's, it's difficult to push much beyond roughly 25
to 70 5K per employee.
In stage two, adding a team helps,
but gains are still incremental.
So you'll, you'll see improvement,
but efficiency is still constrained by coordination
and leadership dependency.
It's in stage three process driven organizations
where value really starts to compound.
So this is where earnings per employee can jump
dramatically sometimes into hundreds of thousands
because systems not people are doing the heavy lifting.
If you look at highly mature process driven public
companies, they often outperform smaller businesses
by multiple bolts, sometimes five to 10 x in, in,
in profitability per employee.
Now, that doesn't mean bureaucracy is good,
we certainly don't strive to have that at Empower Labs.
We want a small team of AI enabled people.
However, it, it does highlight something important
that we can learn from,
which is inefficiency often comes from
us being the bottleneck.
In, in small organizations.
In stage four, ai,
augmented organizations push efficiency even further.
So with the right systems
and integration, you know, million dollar plus
earnings per employee become possible.
And in stage five, we start
to see entirely new valuation dynamics, including one
or two person companies reaching billion dollar valuations.
Um, there are potentially some companies out there like
that now, uh, but that surely will be possible very soon.
Another way to look at value is through exit multiples.
Even if you're on here, by the way, not planning
to sell these numbers do matter, especially if growth
through acquisition is part of your strategy, which
for a lot of entrepreneurs it is, um, higher stages
command higher multiples
because they're more transferable, durable and scalable.
So the big takeaway is this,
as businesses move up the stages,
value creation accelerates not because of tools, but
because of systems efficiency and leverage.
That's why moving from stage two to three
and from three to four is
where the most meaningful valuation lifts tend to occur.
Um, there are a number of resource examples here.
I'm not going to take the time to go through each
of these in this live session,
but, uh, perhaps you might wanna come back
and look through this deck, um, on your own time
and just take a look at some of these things and,
and think deeper about where you are at, like
what this means for you.
You, you want to be a bit more granular, uh, about
what stage you are at in terms of process, resource,
and then priorities.
Um, so with that, um, Midori, uh,
do you, do you wanna maybe talk
to everybody about this poll
just to see where everybody's at?
Yeah, absolutely. Thank you so much, Josh for, uh, going
through that in the chat.
I am going to include, uh, the five stages of, uh,
AI enabled business.
So everyone has that at their fingertips, uh, to review.
Uh, and I am also gonna shortly launch a poll.
Uh, and that poll is, is really simple.
It's which stage of AI capability is your organ
organization currently at.
Uh, and we're gonna use, uh, the information
that you all share to kind of inform the discussion that's,
that's, uh, coming up next.
So just give me one moment
and here comes the next poll.
Okay. Thank you. For folks who are answering,
it looks like we have a a lot of folks at stage two,
and we also have folks at stage one and stage three.
Awesome. All right.
Yeah, so it looks like 50% of you are around stage, uh, two,
uh, 25% at stage one and 25% at stage three.
And there are the results for anyone who wants
to take a quick peek.
Okay? So thanks for taking the time
to respond to the poll.
It really gives us a sense of how, um,
the discussions that are coming up.
We're going to go, uh, we are going to take, uh,
about 12 minutes or so, uh, to join breakout rooms.
We're gonna be in groups of, uh, three to four folks,
and we really want you to take this time
to introduce yourselves and answer, uh, three questions.
And it's just the three, your company name, which part,
process or function
of your organization is currently at the lowest
of these five stages.
And then which of, uh, which part of your company, um,
is at the highest stage.
So we really wanna get a sense of where your bottleneck is,
and we really want to get a sense of, you know,
where things are going well.
Uh, and so for this two, uh, we're gonna go in a quick sort
of rapid fire round, meaning
that you're just gonna answer these and not dive any deeper.
Might sound like. Hi, I am Adori with Boundless Collective.
I'm a, it's a marketing
and strategic communications consultancy.
Our customer acquisition is at oh one, but our onboarding
and HR is at a three.
Uh, and then after you've gone through this
and everybody's answered, this is the a time when you will,
um, have a chance to share, dive a little deeper,
ask each other more questions,
and provide, um, some insight into what's been shared.
So if that sounds good, I'm gonna, uh, you can take a moment
to reflect on these three questions,
and I will get the breakouts up and running.
So again, we will see you back here maybe in about
12 minutes.
Um, and you don't have
to worry about keeping an eye on the time.
You'll automatically be added back into the main room.
Okay. Hopefully you're all seeing your invitations now.
Okay. Looks like we're a
little bit ahead of schedule.
That's okay. Okay.
You know, it's, again, it's, I think I'm,
I'm covering everything and you know, you, I want to get,
be high level with people so they understand the stages,
they're talking about it.
So we're dealing with everybody from stage mostly,
mostly people are from stage one
or stage three, which is good.
Mm-hmm. Um,
That's quite a bit a big difference from the last cohort,
from the video that I saw.
It sounded like a lot of folks were, uh,
like some people were identifying their themselves at three
and four, like a good chunk.
Yeah. And again, like a lot of people tend to
over vote, right?
So the, you know, like,
it's like when I mentioned stage four,
like if you look at our company internally,
we have some stage four sort of what I'll call workflows,
meaning like, there are workflows that are
mo like primarily automated with ai, um,
that involves human qc, right?
Um, and so,
but it doesn't mean the whole business is that way.
Like most people, when they say stage four,
they're probably like, oh, I have my, I'm making this up,
but like, I'm an agency and my whole onboarding
and everything is all, and that's, that's stage four.
Like, hey, if you plug somebody comes in
and it's all automated on the backend,
what's delivered the calls, there's a lot
of really cool capabilities, um, with, with things like this
that, um, are, are possible.
And so it's good.
It's, it's, it's all about,
today's all about just getting clear, like, where are you,
which is gonna be anybody from stage one to three?
And then how do you go from one to two, two to three,
three to four, right?
Um, people will probably ask, you know,
can they go from one to three?
And, uh, it's
with a very small company, it's certainly possible.
Mm-hmm. Um, but again, it's, it's just about
defining process of what good looks like
and then kind of building from there.
A lot of people, smaller companies have speed that, um,
is actually a really good thing in terms
of implementation opposed to, to larger ones.
And do you find that there are, um, predictable places
where people are identifying themselves at a one
and identifying themselves at a, at a three, like in terms
of where folks really need that human piece
or, you know, it's a cult of personality
or what have you, um, and other places that are easier to
Well, it's, it's more, it's more
or less just what the, like what stage are you at, you know,
because it's, it, how is your company currently led, right?
So is are you, are you an owner operator that's working,
you know, 60 hours a week,
and if you took a vacation for a week, would your,
would your business not exist?
I mean, that's kind of that stage one in, in a nutshell.
Mm-hmm. Uh, we're even excluding ai, those are sort of,
obviously we're here for sort of ai, you know,
implementation, but it's really just saying like, Hey, I'm,
I'm an owner operator business.
I'm involved in pretty much everything,
which means I'm the bottleneck.
Next step is team. So like, I now have, you know,
a director layer or managers, whatever you wanna label them.
Mm-hmm. And so like, they're basically meeting with me
as the owner, but then they are sort of leading the people
that are doing the things in different departments
or whatever that would look like in a company structure.
Um, and,
and like I went over, it's like, then you have process
and everything is very, very clear.
So everyone understands
and there's alignment from founder to director layer
to people all the way through, which is incredibly
challenging, um, to pull off.
Um, but it's, it's really the main part of this cohort.
Mm-hmm. The big piece of it.
So if once people, whether they're one person
or they're a hundred
or a thousand employees, if they see
what good looks like in every area of the business, which is
what we're gonna sort of be doing
after this initial, like, like Friday's session
with the Empower operating system, that's what, what sort
of starts that like, market to lead, lead to sale, sale
to delivery, doing these assessments is going
to create process, um, which is what everything is.
Okay. Cool. I'm gonna go to the restroom real quick.
Mm-hmm.
I think we got another two minutes.
Okay. Cool. Sounds good.
Yeah. You know what's funny, I just thought of this
is if we,
'cause this is like the first like session,
I'm like presenting a lot of content.
Um, if, if I tend to go quicker,
if we notice that mm-hmm.
Um, then maybe you
and I like, we'll make like the breakouts
like 15 minutes for something.
Yeah. Yeah. You know What I mean?
We can make that small adjustment
because people do love connecting in the breakouts too.
And they, they all, I know in the laugh,
like they always say like, oh, I got cut off
and we were, I was, I was right in the middle of finishing.
So it, it is a probably the perfect amount of time to not,
you know, 12 minutes, 10, 12 minutes,
but we can always, uh,
adjust the time in the settings and stuff, so,
Okay.
Uh, yeah, I mean, I think that, that,
I think people generally like to, to connect
and once you can start going,
you really start going. Um, yeah,
Especially this one. Like, it's,
it's running through a lot
and then, you know, I'm about to, um, you know,
it's definitely a, a good amount of stuff
and now the evolving your business is is kind of 10 minutes.
Um, um, so I'll go through that
and then we're in the, the next step.
So if you want take a few minutes to kind of recap,
you know, I put like, you can facilitate in the chat too,
like key insight, uh, that emerged for you.
Like what are you looking for,
is there anything you're looking forward to the most?
However you wanna say that.
But we can take a, a few minutes there as well.
Yeah. So maybe we can actually call on people
or, um, you know, read those, um, chat pieces out.
Um, just because if
You do, if you do that like a tip, I learned just
because, um, a lot of times people will talk for a while.
Like on the last cohort there was a few people like Wuhan
and a couple other people, they were like,
uh, they were talkers.
And so I'd be like, Hey, Midori, uh, you wrote
whatever it says, and then I'm like,
would you mind giving us 30 seconds for that?
Okay. Yeah. So just sort of give capping people at, at a
Yeah. It's just like a small tag
to throw on.
So, and, and again, it doesn't always work,
but yeah, you can definitely, um,
Yeah, that's, that's helpful just to, uh,
keep, keep to time.
Yeah. So
I,
I see some smiles.
That's good. It's always good from the breakout room.
Oh, we were having fun in our breakout room.
Oh, well, welcome back everyone.
Thank you for, uh, having those discussions today, hoping
that people are not gonna be chat shy
and we'll share a key insight, uh,
that emerged for you in the chat.
We would love to, we would love to see what, uh,
what came up for folks.
Well, we had pe two people joining the cohort the second
time, which is a really good sign for me.
And, uh, it was really cool to understand how,
how the different stages are
and, uh, what the challenges are.
They're very different,
but somehow also comparable, I think.
Yeah. It's all about going from one to two, two
to three, three to four, right?
Yeah. Game of business. We're all planned.
Um, you can, uh, chime in if, if you like. Sure.
Uh, I just, uh, committed to, uh, deep, you know,
seriously following the instructions.
You guys have gotten like really focused on that.
It, it, uh, and I, in the first cohort, I was kind
of bouncing around all over the place, uh, you know,
following my own, uh, intuition.
No, no, no. We're gonna, could do it your way this time
and encourage everybody to go there.
Hey, Don, we're, we're gonna take the compliment.
Thank you very much. And, uh, I'm glad,
glad you're gonna be more systematic about it.
Trust me, we, I gave a lot
of those warnings from people like you.
I'm like, look, you're gonna, and we're not even really in
the thick of anything, right?
But once you start seeing possibilities, people to,
you know, it's just human behavior.
We're all guilty of it a little bit,
but you start to, oh,
I could do this over here, I could do this.
And that's when towards the end
of the cohort people became incredibly overwhelmed.
So I don't know if that was you as well on the first
Time. Correct. Exactly.
Uh, Lee, you said we had a wonderful convo about
leveraging AI to augment proven,
person driven delivery of services.
That's awesome. Rather than replacing Excellent.
Anybody else wanna share?
I mean, if you don't wanna type, you can unmute yourself
and we'll, before we dive back into things,
For me personally, personally, it was interesting to see
that, um,
in some areas we have established a
certain level of maturity.
Uh, for example, we are in like stage three
with the processes and everything,
but on the other hand, in some other areas, uh, we discussed
that, we found out, okay, hey, s**t,
we are in just level one.
So everybody, everything is bound to one person,
uh, which is not good.
So it is really not that easy to find like
that one maturity level that you have across all
of your company, because it might differ from area
or product service, administration and so on. Yeah.
Yeah. No, thank you for sharing.
And, and for clarity, um, most businesses, Tim,
are actually in the same position, right?
We all sort of took a poll
and it seemed like everybody said,
or the vast majority are either stage one or stage three
and some stage two,
but you know, internally at Empower Labs in, in terms
of stage four, we internally have completely automated
workflows with ai, with some QC involved.
I know I certainly do in terms of, of acquisition
and lead to market and, and lead to sales cycle.
There's a lot of really cool tools.
And I'll, as we go through the course
and I teach the sales thing, I'll, I'll sort of share all
that stuff with you if it's helpful.
Um, but that doesn't mean the entire company, Tim, is,
is at stage four, right?
So for everybody, like that's just, uh, an awareness
that, that we all should have.
And, and to that point though, whether you're at trying
to go from one to two or or two to three or
or three to four, that's
what I meant about focusing on one thing.
Meaning as we go through this
and you sort of understand
what good looks like throughout each area of your business,
um, AI is gonna create process, which we're,
we're heavy on today, right?
But then towards the end, when you do that in every area
of your company, at the end,
you're gonna focus more on implementation.
And the implementation is going to be
what AI says is your highest driver.
That, again, I'm not going to have the context.
It's gonna say, tied to your strategic initiatives, this is
where you should focus and this is
that process implementation,
and that's gonna be your one thing, whether it's sales
or operations, hr, right?
Um, and perhaps creating a workflow to hiring onboarding,
like I come from the agency space.
I mean, whatever your one thing is going to be,
it's about going, let's call it to stage four.
And then that can be launched, revised,
and optimized in about 90 days.
Then you can go do the second thing, which could,
let's say you go from marketing, marketing to sales,
and that's Tim, where eventually when you start looking at
things in a calendar year.
Um, some of you all were on the beta,
but I mentioned on this call earlier, one
of the biggest drivers that you're not going to really see
until about a calendar year
once people become AI enabled is revenue per employee.
That metric is absolutely what is a, a key focus
for us internally, but also for you all as business owners.
You're just going to start to see that you can eight
to 10 x someone's output.
It's not about AI replacing them, they just get much,
much higher bandwidth as well as speed and efficiency
and the quality of output once they have the context.
So all of those things sort of, uh, equate
to the revenue per employee, EBITDA per employee,
however you sort of measure that.
So I will say at the beginning, for business owners, that's,
that's a very key metric,
and again, you kind of won't really see that uptick
for about a calendar year.
Um, but those are things internally we're,
we're very, very keen on.
So hopefully that's helpful. And then, yeah, I'll,
I'll dive into the rest here so you all can see kind
of the part three here.
Alright, so finishing up part three is,
is exploring
how your business might move from one stage to the next, right?
Just like I was sharing with Tim there.
So let's wrap this section with just some practical steps
that you can take to evolve your business.
Um, and, and the first step is literally just honesty.
Um, we all need to just clearly
and objectively assess
what stage we're actually at today.
And this isn't a judgment, it's just a fact, right?
Once we're, we're honest about where we are, we can,
we can talk about it, plan around it,
and sort of move forward intentionally.
It's Jim Collins, great book from Good
to Great, if you're all familiar.
It's, it's just fact.
So that, that's what we want to focus on today.
Second is document everything. This is key.
Document everything before you automate anything.
And I can tell you firsthand, someone in the last cohort,
uh, they joined
and probably by maybe session four, they started to see
what was possible and they started asking questions, Hey,
can I just start working on automating blank?
It happened to be sales for this gentleman.
But the answer is, you can do that
and you are probably going to want to do that at some level,
but, um, it, it's gonna be tempting
to jump straight into automation,
especially with all the tools available.
But again, automation only works well.
But when it's built on clear process as the,
the main hook from today.
So if something isn't documented,
automating it usually just scales confusion.
The good news is that documenting process doesn't have
to be perfect or overwhelming.
We are going to focus on creating processes
and SOPs first, using AI to accelerate that work
and then improving them over time.
Remember, progress beats perfection here.
Third is it's important to recognize
that delegation is a form of automation.
So whether you're, you're delegating to a person
or to an AI system, the mindset there is the same.
You still need to define what good looks like,
even if you don't yet have a full team.
But, but thinking in terms
of delegation prepares you for scale.
Fourth, start
with augmentation in one business function, as I've mentioned.
So rather than trying to document
and improve everything at once, pick a single area,
one domain and focus there.
This will keep the work actually manageable
and helps you build momentum without getting overwhelmed.
And, and finally, to, to move to,
to full digital automation.
You know, only after augmentation is working.
If we automate too early,
we risk locking in poor quality outcomes.
When augmentation works first with humans
and AI collaborating effectively,
automation becomes far more powerful
and way less frustrating
and confusing on the leadership side.
Okay, finally, why process management matters
now more than ever.
So for most of you from the poll, like you, you're likely
operating somewhere between stage one and three.
And those stages, um, you know, they're missing or,
or unclear process makes everything harder,
especially like resource allocation,
prioritization, and decision making.
That's why we're, um, I'm glad to hear this from Don,
but like, that's why we are not skipping the fundamentals.
So this session, session two
is intentionally focused on laying the foundation.
Before we go deep into the individual drivers of value
inside your business using the Empower operating system,
we need a solid base and process
and documentation are at that base.
The the first priority is simple build better systems.
If you already have processes, right, like a lot
of you have done this, you went to the beta cohort,
we will refine and strengthen them,
or at least that's my suggestion.
Um, if you don't, we will, we'll, we'll use AI
as a thought partner to, to sort
of help you create them in a fraction
of the time it would normally take.
That's one of the, the biggest advantages AI gives us right
now, just speed without sacrificing structure
and quality of output when it has full
context of your business.
The second reason process matters now is
that AI unlocks things that were sort
of previously impossible tasks that were too complex,
too time consuming, or too expensive to systematize
before are now realistic, but only if process exists.
I, I can give a a a personal example.
You know, Hayden is, is a, a, a big time visionary.
Um, and, you know, he, he's kind
of like a creative visionary.
And early on in, in our company, um, you know, I'm a partner
and on the leadership team, he was pushing for all us, um,
to, to really start experimenting with vibe coding.
I'm not sure if any of you know what vibe coding is.
I don't need to go too deep into it,
but essentially it's, um, making anybody can be a developer.
So, you know, rather than building something
with HTML on CSS and JavaScript and JS
and all these program languages, you have to be a programmer
or, you know, a software engineer.
You just open AI
and you could say, create a landing page
that the headline says this, and the sub headline says this,
and put a call to action button that says, book a call,
and you hit the button and it creates the page instantly.
And, uh, if I'm being honest, I I was sort of like resistant
to this because I don't wanna be a programmer.
Uh, it's not sort of like a passion of mine,
but, uh, it, it's a perfect example of that resistance
to change because I, I actually didn't really understand
what he was trying to get me to see,
and is that I don't wanna be a programmer.
That's not something I aspire to be perhaps ever.
Um, however, once I started vibe coding,
very simply creating pages, landing pages and, and opt-ins
and, and applications
and all of these different things
by literally just typing in an AI chat.
I use Gemini for that, if, if any of you are familiar.
But, um, it, it started to let me see that I
of something that I would've needed a web
team in the past, right?
I come from the marketing, marketing agency world.
You might need a copywriter, you might need a,
let's call it a web guy.
So a person to build the pages and do integrations
and do all of these different things
you can just do yourself.
And, and saving endless, endless amounts of time, um,
efficiency and quality of output without having
to add more people, which, which really aids to what a lot
of people have as a goal in terms of,
of becoming AI enabled in their company.
So, circling back without process, AI has nothing
to work with, with process AI becomes a multiplier.
So if you're watching this
and process documentation hasn't been a strength in the
past, that's okay.
This is the moment to change that without fear,
without overwhelm,
and with far more leverage than ever before.
And you will all start to see what's possible.
So, doing this work now, like Don said, uh,
prepares you for what comes next.
So leading to enabling stage four
and stage five exploration, um, you know,
where AI can truly be embedded into
how the business operates.
All right, um, now I'll throw it over to Midori,
who's gonna kind of walk you through the,
the next steps following this session.
Thanks so much, Josh.
Uh, so we covered an awful lot of content today.
Uh, and, uh, I just wanted to walk you through
what comes next, what you're gonna be finding, uh,
in circle in the curriculum section.
Uh, so we want to make sure that you repeat, uh, you
complete the following five things.
So number one, two, and three. Here are some quick readings.
Know your customer lifecycle.
Explore the three layers of business processes
and learn how RACI connects people and process.
So each of these are, uh, three readings
and they're followed by a quick quiz.
So if you all can, uh, go through
and complete those, that would be great.
Uh, and then finally, we have, uh,
the, uh, Claude pieces.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going
to add shared language to your master prompt.
Uh, and this is going to give you three separate artifacts,
and you're gonna add that shared language, master prompt,
uh, and those three artifacts to your cloud project.
Uh, and then from there, you're also going
to start one new chat,
which will also become another, uh, new artifact.
And that is the add your research
resources to your master prompt.
Uh, so by Friday, the hope is that, uh, in your instance
of Claude, assuming you're, uh, working
with a fresh instance, you'll have two chats
and five artifacts.
Um, anyone who has any questions about this
or about all the material we've covered,
or anything else that's sort of come up, uh, for you
between session one
and session two, we do have a few minutes for a q and a.
Uh, we're a small enough group, so feel free to either, uh,
unmute and, um, ask your question to the group,
or, you know, I'll be monitoring the chat as well.
Okay, before we get to the q
and a, I just wanna, uh, go a little bit deeper here
and then also show you, um, I'm gonna share my screen
and just show everybody exactly what Midori covered.
So just to go deeper here with high level details, um,
there's a number of exercises
and quizzes in the curriculum for session two.
So these exercises are simply reading, by the way,
they're not long, uh,
but we're going to introduce some language,
as she mentioned, around knowing your customer life cycle.
And then we're going to have like small quiz about that just
to, um, the, the, you know, about what's gonna be
around understanding those, those three layers.
So just so everyone has a, a, a clear understanding.
And then there's this strategic planning structure layer
and customer like cycle or functional layer.
And then there's enabling processes.
So it's good for each of you to explore those a bit and,
and understand what those are.
As well as some universal definitions like raci, um,
responsible, accountable, consulted, and informed.
Um, you could have different terms in your
company or your organization.
That's totally fine. I would just say please
use these in the master prompt while we'll do,
while we're doing shared learning together,
because, um, it will just make things much more seamless.
And then post cohort, of course, um, you can,
you can go back and, and refine those things with that.
Let me, let me open up Claude,
because I'm, I'm doing this with you all.
Um, so you have, this should be very clear, okay?
Okay. Can you see my screen here?
Okay, so here's, here's the prompts, obviously
that you have those reading
exercises, but this is session two.
This is what we're gonna be doing, okay, this,
here's the first things.
So what, what Midori mentioned, this is
how that's going to operate.
You're gonna see all these prompts,
they're gonna be in the curriculum immediately after,
but this is just high level how you're going to do this.
Okay? So you're gonna copy this,
these first three right here,
business process framework style preferences
and strategic approaches.
You're gonna open this.
And from here, the business process one is pretty long,
but I'm just gonna show you
literally how you're gonna do this.
You're gonna copy it, you're gonna go to Claude,
you're gonna be in your project, right?
Remember the first one? We had one chat in our Claude
project, and we had the one master prompt.
Now I've already done this to Maori's point.
So here's the five things.
This is what it's gonna look like
after you do you complete this session,
but you just go copy that.
You come over here to files and you hit plus
and you hit add text context,
you're gonna name it right here,
and then you're just gonna paste it right here.
That's it, okay? And then you're gonna hit add content.
You're gonna come back, you're gonna do the exact same thing
with style preferences.
Okay? Copy this.
Go back to your project,
hit plus add here,
name it style preferences, paste it, and add content.
So you're gonna add that, those, those,
these context for the first three.
Same thing with strategic approaches.
Then once that context is given, which is how you are going
to be interacting with ai, as we next week start to,
to get deep, then you take your resources.
And this is to add information about your available
resources to your master prompt.
Um, so you, you're gonna copy this prompt.
You're gonna come in and create a new chat,
which will just go right here.
And that is this piece.
This is actually going to create
that artifact no different than we did from the first
version of your master prompt.
It ends right here. And relative to how you all added it,
remember the simplest, simplest way is just to come up here
and put add to project.
Um, reminder, I don't love doing that, just just
for the sole purpose of you don't get to name it.
Um, it will in fact name it whatever is written here.
Um, so if that isn't a, a big deal for you, you're not sort
of someone who, who likes details.
That is the simplest ways just to add it.
I like to download it.
I come back to the project, and at that point I will add
and upload from device.
And if I do that, I will be able to name it.
So you can see all of those different things in the project.
And this is exactly what it will look like when you complete
everything that we just went over.
So hopefully that's helpful.
I just wanna show you guys exactly, um,
just like the seamless, I, I created this, just
so you all see it, and I'll do it along with you.
With that said, we can spend the, the rest
of the time on the call just
answering any questions that you have.
And yeah, we're a small enough group.
I mean, you can raise your hand in Zoom
so we can call on you.
But Midori, were there any questions in the chat, maybe
as the, the session was happening?
Um,
No, I didn't see anything today.
Okay.
Hey, Josh. Um, this is Mike.
Um, I just, uh, had a comment.
I don't know if it'll be helpful for anybody,
but, uh, based on your recommendation, I upgraded
to Claude team yesterday,
and I did notice when I started working on my master prompt,
uh, my personal account was still active until I deactivate
that one, and it did whole information from there,
making it easier to do that transition.
So if you have time left
or still an active personal account, it seems to, uh,
you don't have, I didn't have to copy and paste
or anything to get information into the team.
Okay, thank you. Yeah, and that's good.
Hopefully that's helpful for somebody.
And again, remember a lot of you, um, a lot
of you members coming from the beta, uh, you know, we're,
we're doing everything in the project,
just keeping everything streamlined.
Um, of course you may have it, you know, Mike,
you probably had it in your account preferences as well.
So we can definitely add to that post cohort.
But again, we want to, uh,
anything's worth doing is worth doing, right?
And again, we're, we're, we're starting with the process.
That's really the first step
before we start talking about implementation of everything.
So, um, romaine, I see your hands up, don't you? Go ahead.
Yes. Uh, thank you.
Um, as I was working on my master prompter this morning,
I was wondering how to integrate the vivid vision, so
how the company is going.
So it'll be, uh, I presume in, uh, in the work we are doing,
uh, for next session, it's kind of the a resource, uh,
we will use, for example, the vision.
Yes, absolutely. Okay.
And, and again, you, you know, spend some time on that.
Give it all of the context.
Um, it's, it's your sort of first run,
but as we go through things, some of these assessment, it's,
it's meant to just give deep thought, right?
That means you're, you're, you're thinking on your business.
And I sort of mentioned Romaine, like a, that is, uh,
we've been told in our, our feedback
that's just stuff people don't do, whether it's
a solopreneur or they, a gentleman who actually led
that feedback that has thousands of employees.
He said, this is just the type
of thought I don't think about my business on.
And so this is great. So yeah, these assessments,
especially the first ones, you know,
it won't take you very long,
but it's, it's starting the, the foundations
to have context, which is the key.
Thank you, Josh. Mm-hmm.
Yeah, Jonathan, I'll get to you next.
Yeah, thanks. Um, just a quick question.
I was gonna ask Claude this, but I didn't get to it yet,
but the, the last instructions for the pre-work
for this section talked about, uh, in,
in your Google Drive setting up the, the file structure.
Can you do the same in OneDrive?
I don't, I don't, I can't access a Google Google Drive
due to cybersecurity.
Yeah, I understand. Um, so I don't know that there, I,
I do believe you can integrate it.
So for clarity, this is, this is just sort of sharing,
I assume your file context for Jonathan, for everybody.
So you can right now, um, integrate Google Drive.
Um, I'm pretty positive you can integrate it, Jonathan,
however, you may need to talk to someone in your company
with security settings like that.
You, it can be done, it'll just be through open API opposed
to just as simple Google Drive as like the click
of a button integration.
So we appreciate that.
But yeah, for you and,
and your security settings, it might be, uh, something
that you talk about in-house.
Okay, thank you. Of course. Uh, Benny,
Thanks.
Uh, I am quite new, so I am a, I'm a bit afraid
that I cannot follow.
So the next steps you presented, um,
they follow I guess the, the next steps from the, the pre,
uh, presentation from two days ago.
And, uh, I will be guided in the circle.
So every step, uh, is explained so I can
follow these steps and I will succeed.
That's correct. So just for, just for you specifically,
because you weren't on the first session, um mm-hmm.
So we, we have these live sessions.
Immediately following this, there's going to be access to,
this recording will take some time.
Apologies on the first one.
Um, but, uh, this will be posted in the curriculum and then
after that you will have access
to those prompts that I just showed you.
You'll click a button, it'll open
that doc for you to have those prompts.
And then if you have to go back to this recording,
but once you do your, your first,
like the actual first version,
one of your master prompt, right?
The first foundation of that, which was the first session
is you are going to have one file in your project.
Just one.
Yes. Okay. And
after today, I just sort of walked through it.
If you want help, literally come back
to this and just go to the end.
'cause I, um, we didn't do this, the first couple
of cohorts, but I wanna do it along with you guys
so you can come back as a reference in case there's
anything that isn't clear.
Um, but you're going to add those project files
as text documents first, and it's, it's gonna be in order.
Literally just copy paste, add it to your clawed project,
then go in and create the chat in the assessment
that I just told you for.
Yes. Like mapping out your organization's
resource and kind of assets.
And that's all that you have to do, um, prior
to Friday's live session.
Okay, Thank you.
And then of course, just ask questions, Benny,
message me on circle it,
whether you're doing your version one master prompt,
you have any questions, I'll make sure
you gets squared away.
Thanks. Of course. Alright, any, anybody else?
All right. Alright. Everybody's good.
So I'm gonna, I'm just gonna call on somebody to,
to teach Friday session.
I, I'm all for this. No,
um, I appreciate you guys.
Um, again, we wanna, we wanna make this, uh, as streamlined
and as clear as possible yet, you know,
Friday we're gonna be diving into the
Empower operating system.
I think I know a lot of you operate, um, run EOS internally.
I know I saw that with at least a few of your forms.
So if, um, all of you are familiar
with business operating systems, you know, traction,
scaling up the great game of business, all of those things,
um, that, um, nothing's perfect, right?
But, uh, a lot of pieces from those were pulled
to create the Empower operating system, really
to do assessments on businesses to see, you know, how, uh,
should we invest in a type of company.
It was really like a, a strategy for acquisition
and that's how this has all evolved in Hayden's world of,
of owning dozens of businesses and coming in and,
and, you know, from a leadership percent, uh, standpoint,
like, you know, creating change management for people to,
uh, go from stage one to two, two to 3, 3, 4.
So I'm excited for Friday.
It's gonna, after Friday is
where we really start doing like deep work to show you
what good looks like and then actual create process.
And then we continue to go through every, um,
section of your company.
So, um, last chance for any other questions.
Otherwise we'll finish things up
and I'll, I'll see everybody on Friday on the session.
So Friday will be Hayden
and myself, obviously, uh,
I know the Empower operating system, we use it internally,
but he invented it, so it would make a lot of sense if,
if he leads that session.
Cool. Okay, perfect. Appreciate you all.
Um, like I said, everything, uh,
this recording takes maybe a couple hours,
but, uh, Benny, as soon as, as soon as this session is over,
the assessments and, and all the prompts
and the things I just went over, they will be
inside the curriculum if you wanna just get after it.
And then of course, this recording plus the slides and,
and everything we went over today will be in there for you
to go back to as a resource.
All right. Great. Thanks everyone.
Have a good rest of your day and we will see you Friday.
Thank you, you on Friday. Take care. Bye-bye. Thanks.
Bye bye-Bye. I.